Toggle Site Navigation Menu

#### [About Us](https://www.fightforthefuture.org/about)

#### [Projects](https://www.fightforthefuture.org/projects)

#### [News](https://www.fightforthefuture.org/news)

#### [Contact](https://www.fightforthefuture.org/contact)

#### [Donate](https://www.fightforthefuture.org/donate)

Privacy Policy
==============

Our Privacy Policy

Fight for the Future is a team of real people fighting to make the Internet safer and more accessible to all who use it. When you sign our petitions, make a donation, or join our mailing list, we collect some of your personal information. This allows us to contact Congress on your behalf, to process payments, and to keep you updated on important digital rights issues that need your help.

We get outraged every time we see big corporations and government agencies exploit our personal data for their gain, putting us at risk of fraud, hacking, and abuse. We want you to know that your private data is safe with us, so we wrote this Privacy Policy to help you understand how we use it, and how we keep it secure.

In this policy, “Fight for the Future” refers to our two organizations — Fight for the Future and Fight for the Future Education Fund. So when we say “we,” “us,” or “our,” we are talking about our board members, employees, volunteers, attorneys … everyone who works for our organizations in an official capacity. And when we say “you,” we’re talking about you and everyone like you who uses our websites.

This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, maintain, and disclose information collected from people who use websites we’ve created, like [www.fightforthefuture.org](http://www.fightforthefuture.org/), [www.battleforthenet.com](http://www.battleforthenet.com/), [www.banfacialrecognition.com](http://www.banfacialrecognition.com/), and [www.fightforprivacy.co](http://www.fightforprivacy.co/). Of course, these are just a few examples. We are constantly building new websites to keep the public informed about new threats to their digital rights.

By accessing any of our websites or submitting any forms on our websites, you agree to fully comply with our Privacy Policy. You also consent to the collection and use of any information you provide. If you don’t fully agree to comply with our Privacy Policy or our Terms and Conditions of Use, we ask that you do not access or use our services.

### What type of information does Fight for the Future collect?

Fight for the Future collects two types of information:

* Personally identifiable information  
    In some cases, Fight for the Future asks you to submit information that could be used to identify you. This includes your name, email address, cell phone number, mailing address, and payment information. We only collect this information when you voluntarily provide it to us, and we use this information to fight for your digital rights by messaging your lawmakers, sending you cool merch, and keeping you updated on all the latest news, among other important activities. If you’d like to know what identifiable information we have about you, and to request corrections, you can send an email to [team@fightforthefuture.org](mailto:team@fightforthefuture.org), or write to us at PO Box 55071 #95005, Boston, MA 02205.
* Non-personally identifiable information  
    When you visit our websites, we may collect non-personally identifiable information through Google Analytics or Fathom. This information may include the type of browser and operating system you use, the date and time you visited our websites, the Internet address of the site from which you linked to our websites, which pages you viewed on our websites, and your Internet Protocol (IP) address — a number that is automatically assigned by your internet service provider to the computer you used.We may also use small text files called “cookies” to measure aggregate web statistics, such as collecting the number of users to our websites, the number of repeat users, the most popular webpages, and other purposes. You may choose to set your web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you do so, however, some parts of our websites may not function properly.You can learn more about how Google uses information collected from sites that use its services by visiting [policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). If you want to opt out of participating with Google Analytics, download the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on at [tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). Information about Fathom can be found at [usefathom.com](https://usefathom.com/).

### What does Fight for the Future do with the information we collect?

First and foremost, we use your personally identifiable information for the very reason you submitted it to us. For example, if you order a t-shirt from our store to show your support for net neutrality, we need to collect your mailing address so we can make sure your t-shirt is delivered to your home. Or, if you sign up for our email list, we will use your email address to send you important updates on digital rights issues. If at any time you wish to stop receiving our email, please complete the form available at [fightforthefuture.org/subscription](https://www.fightforthefuture.org/subscription). We also include instructions on how to unsubscribe at the bottom of every email we send.

Similarly, if you provide Fight for the Future with your phone number, you consent to receiving phone calls and text messages from us about events, advocacy, membership and other issues. But if you wish to be removed from our phone list, you can text STOP to 687-88 at any time. We will then send you a message confirming that you have been removed from our text list. Please do not reply to that message, as it may result in your being re-subscribed.

We may also use some of this information to customize our content and communications with you based on your individual interests, location, and previous interactions with Fight for the Future campaigns.

And all that non-identifiable personal information we collect? We use it to diagnose technical problems and improve the usability of our websites. Imagine, as an example, that our analytics show us that lots of people are visiting a website to sign a petition, but very few of those people are actually signing the petition. We can then investigate whether there is a bug with our form, or if our website design needs to be changed to encourage people to take action. That helps us focus our time and efforts where they are needed the most.

### How Fight for the Future protects the information we collect

Fight for the Future treats your personal data as though it were our own. We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices, and we implement security measures to help protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information. We do our best, but always remember that no data transmission or storage system is guaranteed to be 100% secure.

### Does Fight for the Future share my personal information?

There are certain circumstances under which Fight for the Future might share the information we collect. Keep in mind that we strive to collect and retain only the information we need in order to effectively fight for your digital rights. We can’t give anyone what we don’t have, so share your data with Fight for the Future — and all corporations, non-profits, and government agencies — accordingly.

Sometimes we need help from third-party service providers to operate our websites and administer activities on our behalf, such as collecting donations and completing online orders for merchandise. These third-party vendors need access to some information about our users. However, they are required to protect the confidentiality of the information, and to use it only for the limited purpose for which it was provided.

Sometimes we partner with like-minded organizations, working together so that our coordinated actions have a bigger impact on public policy. If you provide your information to us as part of one of these actions, we may share personal information about you with those like-minded organizations. When these like-minded organizations receive your information, they may use it according to their privacy policies. But don’t worry; we will always let you know when this might happen. Just make sure you read the legal info attached to every form on our websites before you submit.

Whenever you sign a petition on our websites, it’s possible we might share your name and other personal information with public officials or outside companies related to the petition. So if you sign one of our petitions to contact Congress in support of net neutrality, we are definitely going to contact Congress and tell your lawmakers that you signed our petition in support net neutrality.

It is possible that Fight for the Future could be legally required to share personally identifiable information about you. We reserve the right to share your data if it’s legally necessary, or out of safety concerns.

Fight for the Future may also share personally identifiable information in connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of its business to another company. And, of course, we may share personally identifiable information about you if you give us your explicit consent.

Finally, we may share generic. aggregated demographic information not linked to any personally identifiable information with third parties.

The above excludes text messaging originator opt-in data and consent; this information will not be shared with any third parties.

### Fight for the Future and third-party websites

Fight for the Future may provide links from our websites to other websites that we don’t own or operate. Examples include news sources that back up our arguments, like-minded organizations that have teamed up with us on an important campaign, or social media networks where you can help spread urgent information.

We don’t control the content or links that appear on third-party websites, and we’re definitely not responsible for the practices these websites employ. These websites and services have their own privacy policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website — including websites that have a link to or from our websites — is subject to that website’s own terms and policies. This Privacy Policy covers only information collected through the use of Fight for the Future websites.

### Does Fight for the Future respect “Do Not Track”?

You bet we do.

If you aren’t aware, certain web browsers allow you to set your privacy preference to Do Not Track (DNT). We respect DNT signals, and when recognized do not load analytics.

### Compliance with Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act

Protecting the privacy of kids is especially important. For that reason, none of our websites ever collect information from individuals who we know to be under 13 years old, and no part of our websites are structured to attract anyone under the age of 13.

If Fight for the Future becomes aware that we have any information about anyone under 13, we will promptly delete the information.

### California privacy rights

If you reside in California and have provided your personally identifiable information to Fight for the Future, you may request information once per calendar year about how we disclose certain categories of your personally identifiable information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. Send your request by emailing [team@fightforthefuture.org](mailto:team@fightforthefuture.org).

### Changes to this privacy policy

Fight for the Future may update this Privacy Policy at any time at our sole discretion. When that happens, we will update the date at the bottom of this page. Changes become effective upon posting. Your continued use of our websites after the Privacy Policy has been modified means that you accept the revised Privacy Policy.

We encourage you to check this page frequently for any changes so that you can stay informed about what information Fight for the Future collects and how it uses that information. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this Privacy Policy periodically and become aware of any modifications since your last visit.

### Questions about our privacy policy

If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy or anything relating to our websites, please contact us by emailing [team@fightforthefuture.org](mailto:team@fightforthefuture.org).

_  
Last changed: 2/2020_

#### Donations information

Your credit card information will be used only for transactions through our secure online payment system. Fight for the Future does not retain credit card information.

* * *

For press inquiries, please contact us at:  
[(508) 474-5248](tel://5084745248) or [press@fightforthefuture.org](mailto:press@fightforthefuture.org)

For donation information, please email:  

All other inquiries, contact:  

No copyright intended!
